(Just For Love)
（只为爱）
(Episode 4)
（第4集）
I just heard something.
我刚刚听到一些事情。
Actually Xu Yu Ling went to interview Fang Shi Yan yesterday.
其实徐玉玲 昨天就去采访了方世言。
A moment. Why are you so calm?
片刻。你为何如此冷静？
I went to the editor's office this morning…
今天早上我去了 编辑部……
and saw Xu Yu Ling hand over the draft.
就见 徐玉玲递出了草稿。
I was thinking…
我刚在想…
no interview task these two days either.
这两天也没有面试任务。
Why did he submit the draft?
他为何提交草案？
Then, while I was in the pantry earlier,
然后，当 我早些时候在食品储藏室时，
I heard that he actually went to interview Fang Shi Yan.
听说他居然 去采访方世言了。
You know what's even more annoying?
你知道 更烦人的是什么吗？
I've read your interview outline, haven't I?
我已经读过 你的采访提纲了，不是吗？
He literally copied your entire interview outline.
他简直抄袭了 你的整个采访大纲。
What do you think all this is?
你认为这一切是什么？
For real.
真正的。
Tuan Shi.
Tuan Shi.
Did I say it wrong?
我说错了吗？
I did not follow the framework and interviewed question after question,
我没有遵循框架， 面试了一个又一个问题，
but Shi Yan must have known it was the same outline of the interview.
但施言一定知道这和 采访的大纲是一样的。
And, he answered the same question twice.
而且， 同样的问题，他回答了两次。
Xu Yu Ling memang penipu.
Xu Yu Ling memang penipu.
Yu Ling, you are so great.
于凌，你真是太棒了。
You can interview Shi Yan.
You can interview Shi Yan.
Yes, Yu Ling, you are really great.
是的，玉玲，你真的很棒。
Just a small thing. You two, work hard.
只是一件小事。 你们两个，努力吧。
- Did you hear that? - Loud and clear.
- 你听到了吗？ - 响亮而清晰。
The interview went awry and the transcript of the interview was stolen.
采访出了差错， 采访笔录被盗。
I was also played while riding a horse.
我骑马的时候也被玩过。
Oh God.
天啊。
How many embarrassing things have I done in front of him?
我在他面前做了多少丢脸的事？
Actually, this Shi Yan was quite good.
其实这个施言还是不错的。
He was a busy man, but he still received two interviews.
他虽然很忙，但 还是收到了两次面试。
He seems to be quite patient with you.
看来他对你很有 耐心。
If you want to say that the people are quite good.
如果要说 人还是挺好的。
He holds a grudge.
他心怀怨恨。
His mood changes quickly.
他的情绪变化很快。
He also likes to see people doing embarrassing things.
他还喜欢看到 人们做令人尴尬的事情。
But, if you want to say that the person is not good.
但是，如果要说 这个人不好的话。
He doesn't seem to have any malicious intent.
他看起来并没有什么恶意。
But, when interviewed, you don't know what he is thinking.
但当你接受采访时，你 不知道他在想什么。
He is a great actor.
他是一位伟大的演员。
I do not understand this man.
我不明白这个人。
Mr. Shi. Marketing and Finance Department …
石先生。 市场及财务部…
just released the Le'an assessment report.
刚刚发布了 乐安评估报告。
From what we can see now, there is still room for negotiation.
从目前来看， 还有商量的余地。
But, you really consider to…
但是，你真的 考虑过……
Besides that,
除此之外，
where did they get so much money all of a sudden?
他们一下子从哪里弄到这么多钱？
There will always be someone…
总会有人……
who is willing to do something profitable.
谁愿意做 有利可图的事情。
Shu Yi, long time no see.
舒仪，好久不见。
Where are you going? I'll give you a ride.
你要去哪里？ 我送你一程。
Thanks, no need.
谢谢，不用了。
I was alone in the car.
车里只有我一个人。
This car was bought for me by Le Zhi.
这辆车是 乐智给我买的。
I will be working at Mingyu in two days.
过两天我就到明宇工作了。
If you like driving so much, why don't you become a driver?
如果你这么喜欢开车， 为什么不去当一名司机呢？
Who's this?
这是谁？
He has a very nice car.
他有一辆非常好的车。
Why did he just gift you a Mercedes worth 300,000?
他为什么就送你 一辆价值30万的奔驰？
And, you still have to wait a few days before you can go to work?
而且，还得等几天 才能上班？
For something that uncle can achieve with one sentence,
对于叔叔 一句话就能做到的事情，
why do you have to go through so many interviews before you can get in?
为什么要经过这么多 面试才能进入？
It feels like you'd better be quick and work hard as a driver.
感觉 作为一名司机，你最好动作要快，努力工作。
Don't stop here and get busy.
不要在这里停下 来忙碌。
Shan Shan!
Shan Shan!
You are really good at scolding people.
你真的很擅长 骂人。
That was a great relief.
这让我松了一口气。
With his mentality,
以他的心态，
he still dreams of riding in the car that is there...
他仍然梦想 着乘坐那里的汽车......
registration plate with repeating digits.
带有重复数字的车牌 。
He looked down on Shi Yan too much,
他 太看不起石岩了，
and too sure of myself.
而且 对自己太有信心了。
Let him come.
让他来吧。
Ms. Zheng might prefer this car.
郑女士可能 更喜欢这款车。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
Some people can change their car easily,
有些人可以 轻松换车，
but I work hard...
但我很努力...
only to have my interview outline stolen and my interview fail.
结果我的面试提纲 被盗，面试失败了。
Stop saying sad things.
别再说 悲伤的话了。
With your face that can overthrow a kingdom...
你的脸可以 推翻一个王国......
and destroy a country,
并毁灭一个国家，
I, as a woman, can't refuse it.
作为一个 女人，我无法拒绝。
What man can turn you down?
哪个男人 能拒绝你？
Even though my face looks like what you said,
虽然我的脸像 你说的那样
i'm still being played…
我还在被玩……
and left alone in the car.
并 独自留在车里。
I helped you make an appointment with Situ Yi.
我帮你 约了司徒毅。
You know how hard it is to make a date with him now?
你知道现在和他约会有多难吗？
Luckily, we had some connections when we were in school.
幸运的是，我们在学校时就有了一些联系。
We share our experiences in love,
我们分享 恋爱经历，
and I also lent her clothes for appointments.
我还借给 她衣服去约会。
We have some influence relationships.
我们有一些影响关系。
Otherwise, you won't be able to meet him.
不然你就见不到 他了。
Shan Shan, thank you.
杉杉，谢谢你。
That's why I bought you this delicious meal, okay?
这就是为什么我给你买了 这顿美味的饭菜，好吗？
Honestly, darling,
老实说，亲爱的，
Even I, as a woman, can't reject you with that expression.
就连我这个女人，也无法 用那种表情拒绝你。
So, why does Shi Yan treat you like that?
那么，施言为什么要 这样对你呢？
Or, should I say,
或者，我应该说，
all men like to sell expensive?
男人都喜欢卖贵的吗？
So, they talk like they don't like it, and act like real men.
所以，他们说话就像不喜欢那样， 表现得像个真正的男人。
What matters now is not one man's strategy,
现在重要的 不是一个人的策略，
but to retake my headline coverage.
但要重新开始 我的头条新闻报道。
You are so persistent about covering this year's headlines.
你对报道今年的头条新闻如此执着。
I don't want to compete for headline coverage. I just want to…
我不想争夺 头条新闻报道。我只想…
"Prove me that I have the ability to be promoted..."
“证明给我看，我有晋升的能力……”
"to write for digital magazines."
“为数字杂志撰稿。”
You want to write for a digital magazine with a new perspective…
您想 以新的视角为数字杂志撰写文章......
which speaks for the common financial reader,
这代表了 普通的金融读者，
which is different from paper magazines, right?
这与纸质杂志不同，对吗？
I've heard you say that many times .
我听你说过很多次了。
But, from an outsider's perspective,
但从外人的角度来看，
you're still competing for headline coverage, aren't you?
你还在争夺 头条新闻报道，不是吗？
Actually,
实际上，
wouldn't it be great to be a deputy author?
当副作者不是很好吗？
It might be great to be a deputy author,
成为副作者可能会很棒，
but that's not really my goal.
但这并不是 我真正的目标。
Embracing change and writing for digital magazines…
拥抱变革并 为数字杂志写作……
is my professional ideal.
是我的职业理想。
you see,
你看，
when I interviewed Shi Yan,
我采访石岩的时候，
he changed the interview time immediately and we were surprised.
他立即改变了采访时间 ，我们很惊讶。
But, writing for a digital magazine won't be like that.
但是，为数字杂志写作 不会那样。
We can maintain the timeliness of the news,
我们可以保持 新闻的时效性，
and there are various ways of publication.
并且发布方式多种多样。
Just send the link and we can share it.
只需发送链接， 我们就可以分享它。
This has become a new reading habit of people nowadays.
这已成为 当今人们新的阅读习惯。
And, there are also various formats we can choose from…
而且，我们还有多种 格式可供选择……
to convey to the reader.
传达给读者。
So, I will not give up.
所以，我不会放弃。
I have already planned a special coverage…
我已经计划了一次特别报道……
to put in a digital magazine.
放入数字杂志。
If that can be realized,
如果能够实现的话
so I will be one step closer to my goal.
这样我就离我的目标更近了一步 。
Mr. Shi, I'm sorry.
石先生，对不起。
It's time to go back and I'm still bothering you.
该回去了 ，我还打扰你。
It's fine.
没关系。
Let's drink first.
我们先喝吧。
Is something important happening?
有什么重要的事情发生吗？
After we talk about the duration of the day,
当我们讨论完一天的持续时间后，
I always think what you say,
我总觉得 你说的话
and discuss it with the team.
并与团队讨论。
We don't want to lose a great visionary like you.
我们不想失去 像您这样伟大的梦想家。
So, I came this time…
所以，我这次来了……
to talk to you again about the investment amount.
再和你谈 一下投资金额。
Yes.
是的。
I am so glad that you came looking for me at this time.
我很高兴 你这个时候来找我。
But, Mr. Chen, please give me some time.
但是，陈先生， 请给我一些时间。
I understand that.
我明白那个。
Renegotiation will definitely take some time.
重新谈判 肯定需要一些时间。
But,
但，
I have some pressure on my side.
我这边有一些压力。
I'm glad you reconsidered my suggestion.
我很高兴你 重新考虑了我的建议。
I will give you an answer as soon as possible.
我会 尽快给你答复。
Okay.
好的。
If you follow what you say,
如果你按照你说的去做，
you and Xu Yu Ling use the same skeleton,
你和徐玉玲 用的是同一个骨架，
very difficult to know who won or lost,
很难知道 谁赢谁输，
unless you have a way to get new content.
除非你有办法 获得新内容。
You are right.
你是对的。
But, I have to meet him for new content.
但是，我必须与 他见面以获取新内容。
Look for opportunities.
寻找机会。
You two rode horses together yesterday.
你们两个 昨天一起骑马。
That counts as a bit of a personal connection, right?
这算得上是一种 个人联系吧？
I don't even have his WeChat,
我连他的微信都没有
how can that be called a personal relationship?
这怎么能 称为私人关系呢？
After all, he is very strange.
毕竟他很奇怪。
Does it matter if he's weird or not?
他奇怪不奇怪有什么关系吗？
You need to be clear with your goals, Zheng Shu Yi.
郑淑仪，你要明确自己的目标。
You're not just fighting for headline coverage.
您不仅仅是 为了获得头条新闻报道而战。
You fight so that one day,
你们战斗， 以便有一天，
you can destroy that useless man…
你可以毁掉 那个没用的人……
and the girl who stole your interview.
还有那个偷走你采访的女孩 。
You also fight to upgrade the digital magazine…
你还为 升级数字杂志而奋斗……
long awaited.
期待已久。
The goods have been sent to you via express order.
货物已 通过快递发送给您。
Don't forget to check.
别忘了检查一下。
- Who's he? - Someone who is boring.
- 他是谁？ - 一个无聊的人。
Another man has fallen at your feet.
另一个人 倒在你脚下。
So many people are chasing you.
这么多人追你。
None you like?
没有你喜欢的吗？
You do not understand.
你不明白。
My principle is…
我的原则是……
didn't refuse, didn't explain, didn't appeal.
没有拒绝，没有解释， 没有上诉。
After all, he wants to trick me with such basic tricks?
竟然就 用这么基本的招数来骗我？
He looks down on me, doesn't he?
他看不起我，不是吗？
What trick?
什么伎俩？
Use excuses to help me fix something…
使用借口来 帮助我解决问题......
and deliberately left something at my house,
还故意 把东西留在我家，
in order to create an opportunity to meet like this.
为了创造一个 这样见面的机会。
Such a cheap trick, and people still use it today.
如此廉价的伎俩， 至今人们仍在使用。
Speaking of which,
说到这，
I also have something left in Shi Yan there.
我还有 东西留在石岩那里。
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
你为什么不早点告诉我？
That's a great opportunity to meet.
这是一个 很好的见面机会。
Helo.
你好。
Tuan Shi.
Tuan Shi.
Miss Zheng Shu Yi from Financial Introduction is looking for you.
财经导读郑淑仪小姐 正在找您。
Helo?
你好？
Helo, Tuan Shi.
Helo, Tuan Shi.
I think my earrings fell in your car.
我想我的耳环 掉在你车里了。
Did you see it?
你看见了吗？
I don't see.
我没看到。
Earrings are very important to me.
耳环 对我来说非常重要。
Can you search again?
可以再搜索一下吗？
How important is it?
它有多重要？
More important than my life.
比我的生命还重要。
It is important because…
这很重要，因为……
it was left to my mother by my grandmother,
这是 我祖母留给我母亲的，
and my mother gave it to me.
我妈妈把它给了我。
It's a family heirloom...
这是家族的传家宝...
and my wedding present.
和我的结婚礼物。
I plan to wear it at my future wedding.
我计划在未来的婚礼上穿它。
When I saw it, I remembered my grandmother.
看到它， 我想起了我的奶奶。
I haven't seen him in a long time.
我已经很久没见到他了。
My grandmother wrapped it in a scarf with six layers,
我奶奶 用围巾裹了六层，
and keep it for years.
并保存 多年。
Usually, I don't take it out to wear.
一般情况下我不会 拿出来穿。
So, why are you willing to use it this time?
那么， 这次你为什么愿意使用它呢？
This is because…
这是因为…
This is because it is a very valuable heirloom .
这是因为它是一件非常有价值的传家宝。
Only worthy of the important moment when I interview you.
只有在采访你的重要时刻才值得。
I have seen it.
我已经看过了。
Your wedding gift is made of plastic.
您的结婚礼物 是塑料制成的。
About that…
关于那个…
My ancestors were poor and life was very difficult.
我的祖先很穷 ，生活很困难。
They are farmers.
他们是农民。
They don't see much of the world.
他们见识的世界不多。
Although it is made of plastic,
虽然是 塑料材质，
but it was the most valuable item in our family at that time.
但这是 我们当时家里最值钱的东西。
Send it to him.
发送给他。
Miss Zheng, when do you need it?
郑小姐，您什么时候需要？
As soon as possible. I can't sleep without seeing it.
尽快地。 不看它我就睡不着。
Well, I'll send it to you.
嗯，我 发给你。
So.
所以。
I don't want to trouble you.
我不想麻烦你。
I'll go get it myself.
我自己去拿。
Good.
好的。
Shu Yi, what are you thinking?
舒怡，你在想什么？
You met Shi Yan with a pair of plastic earrings?
你是通过一对塑料耳环认识施言的？
Why plastic?
为什么是塑料？
Plastic is one of man's greatest inventions.
塑料是人类最伟大的发明之一。
Plastic has improved human life.
塑料改善了 人类的生活。
Why look down on plastic?
为什么看不起塑料？
What are you saying?
你在说什么？
You've embarrassed yourself like this,
你 就这样让自己丢脸了
and Shi Yan didn't put your phone down.
而施言也没有放下手机。
He also wants to send it to you.
他也想发给你。
He must be interested in you.
他一定对你感兴趣。
Bogang Yunwan?
Bogang Yunwan?
For a residential area with this price,
对于这个价位的住宅区来说，
no need to even think to know that this is the address of Shi Yan's residence.
不用想就知道，这 是施言的住处地址。
Is he so honest?
他有 那么诚实吗？
This is called having no feelings for you?
这叫对 你没感觉？
How could it be…
怎么会这样…
So…
所以…
Just leave me alone in the lobby and go.
把我 一个人留在大厅就走吧。
He doesn't even want to eat with me.
他甚至不愿意和我一起吃饭。
You throw the bait,
你扔下诱饵，
and he immediately sent you the address.
他立即 把地址发给你。
Is he so impatient?
他就这么不耐烦吗？
He is not usually impatient.
他通常不会 不耐烦。
So, there's only one meaning to this.
所以，这只有一个意义。
All man are the same.
所有的人都是一样的。
I'm telling you, in this situation, you shouldn't go.
我告诉你，在 这种情况下，你不应该去。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Just take action that will definitely work, understand?
只要采取 一定有效的行动，明白吗？
I understand.
我明白。
But, not this time.
但是，这次不是。
I have a plan to discuss with Shi Yan.
我有一个打算，要 和施言商量一下。
What plan?
什么计划？
Uncle,
叔叔，
why are you back?
你怎么回来了？
Shouldn't you meet Guan Ji?
你不是应该 去见一下管吉吗？
Didn't you say not to call him Guan Ji?
你不是说 不要叫他管吉吗？
Guan Ji said call him Guan Ji.
管吉说叫他管吉吧。
Uncle hasn't told me why he suddenly came back tonight.
叔叔还没告诉我 他今晚为什么突然回来。
This is my house.
这是我的房子。
If you don't want to see me, go back and live with your grandfather.
如果你不想见我， 就回去和你爷爷住吧。
I will pack my things.
我会收拾我的东西。
Sit in the room. Don't go out unless I tell you to.
坐在房间里。 除非我叫你出去，否则不要出去。
(Bogang Yunwan)
(Bogang Yunwan)
- Thank You. - You're welcome.
- 谢谢。 - 不客气。
Mr. Shi, I am here to take something.
石先生，我来 取东西。
Mr. Shi, are you also interested in Song Le Lan?
石先生，您也 对宋乐兰感兴趣吗？
One coincidence.
一个巧合。
I also really like it. I have all his albums.
我也非常喜欢它。 我有他所有的专辑。
Which of his songs do you like the most?
你最喜欢他的哪首歌？
Why did you suddenly cancel the appointment?
为什么突然 取消约会？
Chen Sheng said you are working,
陈升说 你在工作，
but Yue said you are at home.
但岳说你在家。
So, that must not be for work.
所以，这一定不是为了工作。
Speak up. Maybe you're in love with someone?
说出来。也许你 爱上某人了？
You haven't been in a relationship for three years, have you?
你已经三年没有谈恋爱了，是吗？
I'm too busy to talk to you.
我太忙了，没时间 和你说话。
The more you say that, the more I think it's not about work.
你越这么说，我越 觉得这不是工作的问题。
It's not appropriate to talk now. We'll talk later.
现在不适合说话。 我们以后再说。
Fast. Let's drink.
快速地。我们喝吧。
Hey!
嘿！
How dare you forget me?
你怎么敢忘记我？
No, I haven't forgotten. Cheers!
不，我没有忘记。干杯!
That's too weird.
这也太奇怪了吧。
Is he in a relationship?
他有恋爱关系吗？
Guan Ji.
Guan Ji.
Let's drink. What do you think?
我们喝吧。你怎么认为？
Are you thinking about women?
你在想女人吗？
I go first. Have fun.
我先走了。玩得开心。
- Why are you in a hurry to leave? - Guan Ji.
- 你为什么急着离开？ ——管吉。
Why is he so weird today?
他今天怎么这么奇怪？
- What is happening? - Let's see.
- 怎么了？ - 让我们来看看。
Is there anything else?
还有别的事吗？
Are you busy with work…
你 工作忙吗…
related to Le'an Technology lately?
最近与乐安科技有关吗？
Are you having problems with this?
您有 这方面的问题吗？
My colleague is writing a draft for Lieying.
我的同事正在 为烈鹰写草稿。
I also did the same interview with Mr. Chen from Le'an.
我也对乐安的陈先生进行了同样的采访。
If I'm right,
如果我是对的
there may be different opinions in Yunchuang…
云创可能有不同的意见……
against Lieying and Le'an.
对阵烈鹰和乐安。
Lieying weighed in secretly and openly in an interview…
烈英 在接受采访时或秘密或公开地发表意见……
that Yunchuang will invest with them,
云创将 与他们一起投资，
and Le'an has expressed the same idea.
乐安也 表达了同样的想法。
But, you said in the last interview that you…
但是，您在 上次采访中说您...
appreciate technological innovation more...
欣赏科技创新更多...
and core technology autonomy,
和核心技术自主权，
so you are more inclined towards Lean Technology.
所以你更倾向于 精益技术。
But, there may be a different opinion in Yunchuang.
但是，云创可能有不同的看法。
If Guan Capital wants to join,
如果冠资本想加入，
so their opinion is also very important.
所以他们的意见 也很重要。
So that's why you've been so busy lately.
所以这就是你 最近这么忙的原因。
So?
所以？
I happened to be doing a personal interview with Chen Kang.
我碰巧正在对 陈康进行个人采访。
So, I want to use your interview as an opportunity…
所以，我想以 你的采访为契机……
to do an exclusive interview series…
进行 独家采访系列……
before you finish this.
在你 完成这个之前。
I want to invite some related parties,
我想邀请 一些相关人士，
such as Yunchuang, Le'an and Guan Capital, in discussion.
云创、乐安、 冠资本等都在讨论中。
what do you want to drink
你想喝什么
Lemon juice, thank you.
柠檬汁，谢谢。
do you want ice?
你想要冰吗？
Oh my god, you are so handsome.
天哪，你太帅了。
What?
什么？
Son.
儿子。
If you are right,
如果你是对的，
Why do you think I will succeed?
为什么你认为 我会成功？
If I do as you say,
如果我 按照你说的去做
How much headline coverage can you get?
您可以获得多少头条新闻报道？
There is a girl here.
这里有一个女孩。
Female friend?
女性朋友？
Shi Yan had a female friend?
施言有女性朋友吗？
Tuan Shi,
Tuan Shi,
did i bother you and your girlfriend?
我打扰 你和你女朋友了吗？
Please consider my suggestions carefully.
请 仔细考虑我的建议。
Female friend?
女性朋友？
The woman in the room,
房间里的女人，
isn't she your girlfriend
她不是你女朋友吗
Not.
不是。
Good, if that's the case.
很好，如果是这样的话。
Good?
好的？
What kind of good is that?
这是什么好事？
Just…
只是…
We can avoid unnecessary misunderstandings.
我们可以避免 不必要的误会。
Misunderstanding?
误解？
As an example?
举个例子？
So, you're saying my nephew won't get it wrong?
所以你是说我侄子 不会弄错？
Nephew?
侄子？
Nephew? That means…
侄子？这意味着……
It will be worse if your nephew gets it wrong.
如果你的侄子弄错了，那就更糟了。
I go first. Early rest.
我先走了。早点休息。
Who's coming?
谁来了？
I seem to hear a woman's voice.
我似乎听到了一个女人的声音。
Barely.
仅仅。
I almost got into a fight with his nephew.
我差点和他侄子打起来。
If I ran into him earlier,
如果我早点遇见他
Yunchuang special report and digital magazine upgrade...
云创专题报道暨 数字杂志升级...
must end.
必须结束。
He came here without taking this back.
他来到这里 ，却没有收回这句话。
Interesting trick.
有趣的技巧。
What are you looking at?
你在看什么？
Who let you out?
谁让你出去的？
Who was that person just now?
刚才那个人是谁？
Uncle's girlfriend?
叔叔的女朋友？
Uncle, I've thought about it.
叔叔，我已经考虑过了。
What if I don't go to work for now?
如果我 暂时不去上班怎么办？
Can I go abroad to study?
我可以 出国留学吗？
Studying abroad?
海外留学？
You really deserve to say that?
你真的值得 这么说吗？
Actually,
实际上，
why do people have to do something meaningless...
人为什么要做 一些无意义的事
and it doesn't work?
它不起作用？
Our entire family is elite…
我们全家 都是精英……
who work hard to earn money.
那些努力工作 赚钱的人。
But, no one…
但是，没有人……
there is time to spend money and enjoy life.
有时间花钱 ，享受生活。
So, why can't I be that person?
那么，为什么 我不能成为那样的人呢？
If someone has to spend money,
如果有人要 花钱，
I can do.
我可以。
In high school, you never passed chemistry.
在高中时， 你从未通过化学。
But, you know more about cosmetic ingredients...
但是，你 对化妆品成分了解更多......
from the Chemistry teacher.
来自化学老师。
You were sent to college abroad,
你被送到 国外读大学，
and your english is not good,
而且你的英语不好
but that doesn't stop you from booking a ticket…
但这并不妨碍你 订票……
and travel around the world.
并环游世界。
So, this is not something that doesn't work.
所以，这并不是 行不通的事情。
It depends on whether you want to succeed or not.
这取决于 你是否想成功。
I know I did something wrong.
我知道我 做错了什么。
But, uncle, whatever you want me to do,
但是，叔叔，无论 你想让我做什么，
Uncle can't let me go to work.
叔叔不能 让我去上班。
I never wake up early…
我从来不早起...
and staying up late for college entrance exams.
并熬夜参加 高考。
Should I work…
我应该工作吗...
nine in the morning to five in the evening for a few thousand salary now?
早上九点到晚上五点 现在工资几千？
It's almost the end of the year.
快到年底了。
Why don't we talk about this after the new year.
何不等 过年后再谈这个呢？
Is it okay?
可以吗？
- Tolonglah, pak cik. - Qin Shi Yue.
- Tolonglah, pak cik. - Qin Shi Yue.
The Shi family does not keep useless people.
石家不留 无用之人。
Not bad.
不错。
You really have the potential…
你确实有潜力……
to become an expert without a teacher.
成为无师自通的专家。
You went there and didn't take the earring back…
你去了那里，却没有 把耳环拿回来……
to see him again.
再次见到他。
You create opportunities.
你创造机会。
Smart.
聪明的。
So, you have to contact him immediately...
所以，你得 赶紧联系他……
to arrange a time to go home again.
再次安排时间 回家。
Hurry up.
赶快。
We'll talk later. I still have something to do here.
我们以后再说。我 这里还有事要做。
Smart, so to speak.
可以这么说，聪明。
I did n't take it back on purpose.
我不是 故意收回来的。
But, I don't have the number.
但是，我没有号码。
How do I contact him?
我如何联系他？
I don't know if the special report will be successful or not.
不知道这次 专题报道能否成功。
Alas!
唉!
What should I do?
我应该怎么办？
They all say it's hard to ask you out in person,
他们都说很难 亲自约你出去
I didn't think you came out either.
我没想到你也出来了。
Want to go out or not...
想出去还是不想出去...
depends on who the person is.
取决于这个人是谁。
It's late.
现在已经晚了。
Nothing else to see here.
这里没什么可 看的。
So, why don't we go somewhere else?
那么，我们为什么不去 别的地方呢？
Tonight is a beautiful night.
今晚是一个美丽的夜晚。
There are also beautiful views elsewhere.
其他地方也有 美丽的景色。
Or, should we go get something to drink?
或者，我们应该 去喝点东西吗？
Or, you want to…
或者，你想……
It's time to go somewhere else.
是时候 去别的地方了。
I really want to go somewhere else.
我真的很想 去别的地方。
But, not with you.
但是，不是和你在一起。
I go first.
我先走了。
Goodbye.
再见。
Tuan Shi.
Tuan Shi.
I think my earrings fell in your car.
我想我的耳环 掉在你车里了。
Did you see it?
你看见了吗？
I don't see.
我没看到。
Earrings are very important to me.
耳环 对我来说非常重要。
Can you search again?
可以再搜索一下吗？
How important is it?
它有多重要？
Xu Yu Ling was called to the author's office.
徐玉玲被叫到 作者办公室。
Maybe they want to use the draft?
也许他们 想使用草案？
I have done everything I should have done.
我已经做了我应该做的一切。
Maybe I did what I shouldn't have done too.
也许我 也做了不该做的事。
I'm still confident in my draft.
我对自己的选秀还是很有信心的。
Since I've done all I can,
既然我已经 尽力了
I just leave it to fate.
我只能把它交给命运。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
I want to wash my face to refresh myself,
我想洗个脸 让自己精神焕发
and I will be back to continue exploring the value of some news.
我会回来继续 探索一些新闻的价值。
Regardless, my career still has to go on.
无论如何，我的职业生涯 还得继续。
Don't mention it again.
别再提了。
Shi Yan was really…
施言真是……
I am very unfortunate.
我很不幸。
Shi Yan did not say anything useful at all.
施言根本就没有说什么有用的话。
It's all just normal conversation.
这一切都只是正常的谈话。
If he doesn't want to be interviewed, he should just say it.
如果他不想接受采访， 就直说吧。
Why did he do that to me?
他为什么要这样对我？
He is really useless.
他实在是太没用了。
Just a casual conversation?
只是闲聊吗？
But he gave me a lot of information.
但他给了我 很多信息。
Who knows how he dealt with Shi Yan?
谁知道他是怎么 对付石岩的？
You know that looks really good, right?
你知道这看起来 真的很好，对吧？
Besides, he will do anything to achieve his goals.
此外，为了实现自己的目标，他会不择手段 。
I have already interviewed Shi Yan,
我已经采访过石岩了，
and he was also able to interview Tang Yi.
而且他还采访到了 唐易。
Using his draft? He…
用他的草稿？他…
- Luckily it wasn't damaged. - Thank you.
- 幸运的是它没有损坏。 - 谢谢。
Thank you for the compliment, Yu Ling.
谢谢你的 夸奖，于凌。
Enough already.
已经足够。
Xu Yu Ling did something very unfair this time.
徐玉玲 这次做了一件很不公平的事。
I warned him earlier.
我之前警告过他。
I will put it on the record.
我会把它记录在案。
He will be judged accordingly…
他将受到相应的审判……
during performance and year-end evaluation.
在绩效和 年终评估期间。
Next time, I will avoid this kind of situation.
下次我会 避免这种情况。
Stealing other people's drafts is not allowed.
盗用他人的草稿 是不允许的。
Is the warning enough?
警告够了吗？
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
You want me to fire him?
你想让我解雇他吗？
He's just very depressed.
他只是非常沮丧。
Our brand has not been launched yet.
我们的品牌还没有推出。
Our financial news coverage is very small.
我们的财经新闻报道很少。
It doesn't matter if the company fires him…
即使公司解雇他也没关系……
or he stops himself,
或者他停下来，
others will surely ask why.
其他人 肯定会问为什么。
His career will also be affected.
他的事业也会受到影响。
Why don't you say anything?
你为什么不说话？
I can understand him stealing my interview,
我能理解他 偷了我的采访
but why did he have to steal my interview outline?
但他为什么要 偷我的采访提纲呢？
Doesn't this prove that your interview outline is better?
这不就证明 你的面试大纲更好了吗？
He has proven it with his actions…
他用自己的行动证明了这一点 ……
that you are better than him.
你比他更好。
This time, you have won beautifully.
这一次，你 赢得很漂亮。
For a journalist, the biggest punishment is...
对于记者来说， 最大的惩罚是……
thwarted by the journalistic ability of others.
受到 其他人的新闻能力的阻碍。
I think, this time,
我想，这一次，
he really learned his lesson.
他确实 吸取了教训。
Shu Yi.
Shu Yi.
You still have a long way to go in this industry.
你在这个行业还有 很长的路要走。
Be merciful while you can.
尽可能仁慈一点。
So, Shi Yan chose my interview outline, right?
所以，我的采访大纲是石岩选的 吧？
Of.
的。
Shi Yan was quite principled.
施言很有原则。
This time, he didn't make a fool of the Financial Introduction,
这一次，他没有再愚弄 财务介绍，
he did not refuse Xu Yu Ling's interview.
他没有拒绝 徐玉玲的采访。
He also gives you enough information.
他还给你提供了 足够的信息。
In the end, nobody loses.
最后，没有人是输家。
Look at his EQ and learn from him.
看看他的情商， 向他学习。
There is one more thing. I think you understand it too.
还有一件事。 我想你也明白。
Sama ada Yunchuang atau Shi Yan,
Sama ada Yunchuang atau Shi Yan,
they chose Financial Introduction first…
他们 首先选择了财务介绍...
and then choose one of you two.
然后选择 你们两个之一。
Sister Yi, I understand.
易姐，我明白了。
All my achievements are based on our magazine platform,
我所有的成就都是 基于我们的杂志平台，
which is among the best in the industry.
这是 业内最好的。
So, I want to write better for each article…
所以，我想把 每一篇文章写得更好……
to defend the dignity of Financial Identification.
捍卫 财务身份的尊严。
You are so beautiful and smart,
你是如此美丽又聪明
so don't waste your time getting angry.
所以不要浪费 时间生气。
Thank you for your compliment, author.
谢谢 作者的夸奖。
A beautiful and intelligent person is going to interview now.
一个美丽又聪明的人 现在要去面试。
Helo?
你好？
I'm not busy.
我不忙。
I just had a conversation with a subordinate.
我刚刚和一个下属谈话。
He has a strong will,
他有坚强的意志，
just like me when I was young.
就像我年轻时一样。
I have arranged it with the HR department.
我已经 跟人事部门安排好了。
There is no problem for him to come and be a trainee.
他来当练习生是没有问题的。
But, whether he would be accepted depended on his abilities.
但能不能被录取， 还要看他的能力。
Maybe a lot of people…
也许很多人...
think I'm better suited in research than entrepreneurship,
我认为我更适合 研究而不是创业
but my mentor always encouraged me…
但我的导师总是 鼓励我...
to apply what is learned.
运用 所学知识。
What was more important was the country's industrial development.
更重要的是 国家的工业发展。
So, I have to try it.
所以，我必须尝试一下。
In the past, everyone still used…
以前大家 还是用...
traditional technology to make domestic substitutes for chips.
传统技术 国产芯片替代品。
So, I guess…
所以，我想……
we have to find something new,
我们必须找到 新的东西
although there may be some risks.
尽管可能 存在一些风险。
When we succeed,
当我们成功时，
Our products will be internationally competitive …
我们的产品将具有国际竞争力……
because we do not copy the achievements of others.
因为我们不抄袭 别人的成就。
After listening to your experience, I feel your life,
听了你的经历， 我感受到你的生活，
up to this point, it is very determined.
到现在为止， 已经非常坚决了。
Have you ever worried or hesitated?
你是否曾经担心或犹豫过？
To be honest, when I first got into this field,
说实话，当我 刚进入这个领域的时候，
and learn this technology,
并学习这项技术，
My original intention was to serve the community.
我的初衷是为 社会服务。
But, recently, I suddenly realized…
但最近， 我突然意识到……
with the current development of Le'an Technology,
以 乐安科技目前的发展，
if I'm still blind...
如果我还是瞎子的话...
considering the research stage only,
仅考虑 研究阶段，
regardless of the feelings and opinions of my team members,
不管 我的团队成员的感受和意见，
I am self-important towards them.
我 对他们很自以为是。
Le'an is not just mine.
乐安不只是我的。
It is the hard work of our entire team.
这是我们整个团队的努力。
So, if you ask…
所以，如果你问……
whether I ever worried or hesitated,
无论我曾 担心或犹豫过，
now is the moment I worry and hesitate the most.
现在是我最担心、最犹豫的时刻。
Tuan Chen,
Tuan Chen,
even though the things we face are different,
尽管我们面对的事物 不同，
but i understand you
但我理解你
Some things may just be you who are diligent in the beginning.
有些事情，也许只是 你一开始的努力。
Every step is difficult at this time.
此时每一步都困难重重。
After that, there are people who persevere together, that's not easy either.
后来还有人 一起坚持，这也不容易。
But in this era,
但在这个时代，
have an ideal career and practice it…
有一个 理想的职业并付诸实践……
has become a very lucky thing.
已经成为一件 非常幸运的事情了。
I believe as long as you are strong,
我相信只要 你坚强
the possibilities are unlimited.
可能性是无限的。
Delicious! Very delicious!
可口的！非常美味！
Uncle is not only good at business,
叔叔不仅 生意好，
but also good at cooking.
而且还擅长做饭。
Uncle Aunt's charm no one can resist.
叔叔阿姨的魅力无人 能抵挡。
If you like it, eat more.
喜欢的话就多吃点吧。
When you're full, you can go.
吃饱了就可以走了。
Go? Where to?
去？去哪儿？
Uncle, I suddenly remembered I have an appointment.
叔叔，我突然 想起我有一个约会。
I go first. Eat slowly.
我先走了。 慢慢吃。
Qin Shi Yue,
Qin Shi Yue,
if you dare to walk out of this door,
如果你敢 走出这扇门
I will deactivate your card immediately.
我会 立即停用您的卡。
It's okay if the card is deactivated.
如果卡被停用也没关系。
I will ask my grandfather for money.
我会向 爷爷要钱。
You can ask your grandfather for money.
你可以向 你爷爷要钱。
But, don't you think of coming back here.
但是，你不想 再回到这里吗？
I will change the password. Think carefully.
我会更改密码。 仔细想想。
The best uncle, the most caring about me,
最好的叔叔， 最关心我的，
and my dearest
和我最亲爱的
You won't do this to me, will you?
你不会 这样对我吧？
My love is deep.
我的爱很深。
That's why I discipline you strictly.
所以我才会 严格管教你。
How long until I get home?
我还要多久才能回家？
Give me some time…
给我一些时间…
to adapt to life in China.
适应 中国的生活。
Don't act like you're unfamiliar with the environment here.
不要表现得好像你不熟悉 这里的环境。
You have traveled all over the world since childhood.
你从小就走遍了 世界各地。
You are used to any environment.
你已经习惯了 任何环境。
Uncle,
叔叔，
at least I graduated from a prestigious university.
至少我 是名牌大学毕业的。
Do you want to sell me just like that?
你就想把我卖掉 吗？
And, for just a few thousand a month?
而且，一个月才 几千块钱？
This is a bad deal.
这是一笔糟糕的交易。
You think too highly of yourself, don't you?
你把自己看得太高了 ，不是吗？
A trainer is not worth much.
一个教练的 价值并不高。
If not for money, why do I have to go to work?
如果不是为了钱， 我为什么要去上班？
Our family does not lack money.
我们家不缺钱。
I'm not a problem girl and I don't cause problems either.
我不是一个有问题的女孩 ，我也不会制造问题。
Isn't that enough?
这还不够吗？
Qin Shi Yue.
Qin Shi Yue.
Work is not just a tool to get money.
工作不仅仅是 赚钱的工具。
It also reflects a person's sense of social responsibility…
也体现了 一个人的社会责任感……
and personal values.
和个人价值观。
If you don't lack anything and have energy to spare,
如果你什么都不缺 ，还有余力的话，
so why not do something…
那么为什么不做点什么...
that means for society and others?
这对 社会和其他人意味着什么？
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
If not, sit down and have breakfast.
如果没有，坐下来吃早餐。
After we eat, I'll take you there.
吃完饭 我带你去那里。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Stop the car.
停车。
Good morning. Are you up at night again?
早上好。 你又熬夜了吗？
I have good news. I just heard that our department…
我有好消息。我 刚刚听说我们部门...
will get two new trainees.
将获得两名新学员。
What's so good about it?
它有什么好呢？
Of course that's good news. Don't you want to find a coach?
这当然是个好消息。 你不想找教练吗？
You are very busy.
你很忙。
It would be great if someone worked as your assistant.
如果有人当你的助手那就太好了。
You can also avoid staying awake at night.
您还可以避免 晚上睡不着觉。
Don't joke. It's not certain who will help whom.
别开玩笑了。 谁会帮助谁还不确定。
You know what he's going to do?
你知道他要做什么吗？
No, and I don't care.
不，我不在乎。
I heard he got an interview with an important person.
我听说他接受了一位重要人物的采访。
I think he will go to the interview.
我想他会 去面试。
Looks like he's sure to get headline coverage next.
看来他 接下来肯定会成为头条新闻。
If so, I wish him the best of luck.
如果是这样，我 祝他好运。
You don't have to worry when he's with me.
有他在我身边你就不用担心了。
Although he was a bit late,
虽然他来得有点晚，
it was still his first day at work. He just needs to adapt.
这仍然是他第一天上班。 他只需要适应。
Do not worry.
不用担心。
I work first and we'll talk later.
我先工作，然后 我们再谈。
This is the new intern we hired for our team. Try to see.
这是我们为我们团队聘请的新实习生 。尝试看看。
We do not need an intern at the moment.
我们目前不需要实习生。
Give it to another team.
把它交给另一个团队。
Xu Yu Ling's team already has one.
徐玉玲的团队已经有了一个。
This one has been assigned to you.
这个已经分配给你了。
Lead him.
引导他。
Sis Yi, my workload is heavy enough.
易姐，我的工作量 够大的了。
I really don't have the time and energy to lead new people.
我实在没有时间和 精力去带领新人。
I know your workload is heavy.
我知道你的工作量很重。
That's why I myself found you a helper…
这就是为什么我亲自给 你找了一个帮手……
to help you take pictures and organize materials.
帮助您拍照 和整理材料。
Let's be honest here.
让我们老实说吧。
What is this trainer's background?
这位教练的背景是什么？
All I can tell you is…
我只能告诉你……
we hired him after careful consideration.
我们经过 深思熟虑才聘用了他。
So, I have to accept it, right?
所以，我必须接受，不是吗？
From a work perspective, this is a training task that I am giving you.
从工作角度来说，这是 我给你们的一个培训任务。
From a more personal perspective,
从更个人的角度来看，
consider this as I owe you a favor.
就当我 欠你一个人情吧。
Okay.
好的。
Don't worry, author.
别担心，作者。
I will lead him well.
我会好好带领他的。
He graduated from a prestigious university with high tuition fees.
他以高昂的学费毕业于一所名牌大学。
He is from a rich family.
他来自一个富裕的家庭。
Why doesn't he just sit at home?
他为什么不坐在家里呢？
Why did he come here and work in the news industry?
他为什么来到这里 并从事新闻行业？
Tolerable, and she's beautiful.
可以忍受，而且她很漂亮。
Her qualifications are beautiful.
她的资质很漂亮。
He is our junior editor-in-chief.
他是我们的初级 主编。
He's an excellent student, isn't he?
他是一个优秀的学生，不是吗？
What are you worried about?
你担心什么？
Look at his grades.
看看他的成绩。
His CGPA is just enough to graduate.
他的 CGPA 刚好够 毕业。
Look at his resume. He also included…
看看他的简历。 他还包括……
which he is the champion of the campus singing competition.
他是校园歌唱比赛的冠军。
Obviously he has nothing to show for it.
显然他没有 什么可展示的。
He was just wasted in college.
他只是在大学里被浪费了。
From her background, you can tell she is a spoiled rich girl.
从她的出身就可以看出， 她是一个被宠坏的富家女。
100% sure.
100%确定。
The author really treated you "well".
作者 对你真是“好”。
He gave you troublemakers.
他给了你麻烦制造者。
You can't blame him, and you can't make him angry.
你不能责怪他， 也不能惹他生气。